hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast on this podcast I
help coaches trainers and mentors scale
their businesses and make more money
than they ever imagined with online
digital marketing and strategies to help
them scale to their dream income level I
believe that sales and marketing comes
before anything else in your business
and that that is the most important
thing is making a ton of money now one
thing I want to talk about here today is
about having fun and play and I talked
about this in some earlier episodes and
things like that but we haven't talked
about it in a while and I think that
it's it's a great topic to to bring up
so that's why we're bringing it up here
today there's actually a book on this
called uh the science of
play um it's on Amazon it's a it's a
great book that I highly recommend if I
actually can pull up the actual Title
Here the actual title of it is just just
play by itself but it's really weird if
you just type in play um all that's
going to happen is you're going to
you're going to
see basically it's going to pull up like
Google Play Store and the just looking
up the word play makes it kind of hard
to find the book but if I type in uh
let's see
play
book uh right here yeah here Play How It
shapes the brain opens the imagination
invigorates the Soul by Stuart Brown
It's kind of the the basis line of what
we're going to be talking about here
today is what's in this book it says you
know have you ever noticed how in the
face of a child uh or the Bliss of a
golden retriever running across the y
the lawn uh this is the joy of play by
definition it's purposeless all
consuming and fun and that's really what
I think mentors trainers coaches need to
do more of is play have
fun blow off some steam do things that
might be not so productive waste some
time strategic distraction strategic
procrastination and here's
why it activates parts of our brain for
creativity and so this is something that
when I'm coaching people I tell them I
tell I tell my coaching group this that
when's the last time that you played
when's the last time that you had fun
when's the last time that
you just like didn't do the thing that
produces money in your business but
rather made the pursuit of joy and
wonder a big part of your
life when's the last
time that you
just like a child or like you would as a
teenager did something that maybe you
haven't done as a child or a teenager
and you just went and had some fun I
frequently do this I mean this evening I
just played a little bit of a video game
that I love it's called civilization 6
uh it's a game where you basically are a
civilization leader and you have 500
turns to uh win the game and I and I won
my first round of the game after about
40 hours of playing it over the last
month and something that I gave myself
time takes time to
do but I also had massive creativity
that came out of this and here's why
it's so
important I meet so many mentors
trainers and coaches who tell me I have
no
ideas I can't think of anything to
do I don't know what I should do next I
can't come up with with content ideas I
can't I can't you know what what's the
right thing to do what's the right path
to take I feel so much fomo like what if
I what if I pick the wrong choice in my
business and then I miss out on
opportunities that are out there what if
there's a better opportunity that comes
along and I find that when you give
yourself the opportunity to go
play
and you actually stop operating in this
thinking
that well you
know there can always be a better
opportunity and we got to make sure that
it's that's the right one and that's
perfect and that we're doing the most
productive thing at all times that you
know like get out of this thinking that
you have to be right do do like the
right perfect stuff all the time with
your time or things are going to go bad
for you and things like that it's a
mindset that I see people get into where
like they won't give themselves the
opportunity to make a mistake they won't
give themselves a chance to try things
out and experiment they and this is more
harmful than anything else even though
we think that it's helping us in our
life it's actually a big
detriment it's actually a a major
issue when we operate this
way and so and I and I meet a ton of
people that that do this that that think
this way this this will lead you to you
know constantly optimizing your funnel
because it's never good enough oh a
better idea came along there's a better
idea that came along things like
that my
friends you're going to have to launch
something put something out there even
if there's a better thing coming along
even if there could be a better idea
just to see what happens and just to
gain
momentum and until you do that you're
going to struggle financially in your
business and I meet a lot of coaches and
mentors that end up struggling
financially because it's so
counterintuitive they're like well I
just I don't have time for that crap I
don't have time to waste I got to make
things work well because I have limited
time on planet Earth and limited time
for things to not work well for me and
it's like oh my
goodness and then there's even more bad
teaching out there that tells people
that you know well unless you're making
a million dollars you have no right to
have fun or to watch Netflix or to play
a video game or to spend time with your
family just goofing off until you're
making that much money you got to put
your nose to the grindstone and do the
work and hustle and go hard and it's
just like it's that message is not
something that I resonate with at all
it's something that you know one of my
mentors my mom is my is one of my
mentors because she's been super
successful in
business has taught me is to not operate
that way it's not healthy it's not not
good and the people who do operate that
way I don't see make a lot a ton of
money in their
businesses
um because we're so focused on trying to
control what we can control we're we're
so in a lack mindset we're we're so in a
scare it's a scarcity mindset an
abundance mindset says I have more than
enough time to accomplish everything
that I need to accomplish so I can go
out there blow off some steam have some
fun
and even as I'm saying this right now
you you might be your brain might have
some trouble like you might feel very
uncomfortable even by what I'm saying
right
now and I get
it but I'm telling you I want you to
challenge wherever that belief has come
from who's the first person that taught
you that you don't have time to have fun
and that everything must be
perfect
and that we must you know and in our
brain we we justify it as a spirit of
Excellence
even my
goodness I I just see in my experience
this isn't just Theory this isn't just
thoughts that I thought of one
day like this is time
tested with working with other people
this
is
truth that having fun
playing blowing off some
steam not being so Tethered to I need to
make this work and I need to make sure
every moment is accounted for
perfectly like breaking up with that
thinking and that way of
operating will produce better results
financially for you as a trainer and
Mentor in your business giving yourself
opportunity to be Whimsical and Blissful
and Reckless a little bit
abandoned trying to make sure that every
moment is the most perfectly like you
like that's not
reality and in this business as a coach
as a trainer as a
mentor your best work is going to come
come out of giving
yourself this thing that is
is
natural it's an integral part of your
your
health as much as sleep and nutrition is
and I see that so many people don't give
themselves the opportunity to
play to do things that are fun for them
to do the fun things in life to just
have some
fun more often to do something that has
no
purpose no goal no reason no end outcome
that can be
Quantified and the more opportunities
you give yourself to do
that the better in the long run and it
might be hard for you and it might be a
discipline it might literally Lally
be a discipline that you have to
mentally fight against what's going on
inside
you to give yourself opportunities to go
play and have fun and do the fun things
in
life but I promise you this is somebody
who
has put this to the
test
in the long term it's going to help you
a
lot it's going to help produce positive
results in your
life if you're ever struggling to come
up with ideas if you're ever dealing
with a lack of creativity if you're
stuck if you haven't launched your
funnel yet if you haven't launched your
offer yet this might be the tool that's
going to get you to where you want to go
if you don't know what to talk about
when when it comes to your content if
you don't have the ability to make
decisions and you struggle to decide
because you're afraid of picking the
wrong decision or wasting time give
yourself some time to
play and what I tell people to do is to
come back immediately after you give
yourself that play
time come like come from that state like
go play go do something
fun and while you're doing something fun
right at the end of
it do a little bit of your
work that little bit of a thing that you
might be stuck on and you'll be unstuck
because you're operating from a
different place of neurotransmitters and
the way that your brain is thinking
you're actually operating out of a
different way of wiring your brain for
success
and it's a little bit of a hack to be
able to get your brain to work better
which is really
awesome but in the long term in the in
the big
picture there's a huge net positive by
doing this all right so hopefully this
has just like gotten you to think about
this encouraged you if you want a little
bit more like scientific evidence behind
this again the book play by Stuart
Brown and Chris
vaugh Play How It shapes the brain opens
the
imagination and invigorates the soul the
audio book the paperback it's worth
reading it has all the
scientific uh expert
research on this that I think
will positively change and transform
your life in a big
way
and I think that the topic itself is is
so
important
um again you might not resonate with it
like there's you you might literally
think that this is just a load of
bunk I'm sorry that you feel that
way I want to see you
successful I want to see you making more
money than you ever
imagined and this is a tool that can
help you get
there living a playful life can
transform everything about the world
around
you learning to stop taking life so
seriously can make you a ton more
money
so listen if this has encouraged you
share this with somebody share this
message with people I want this message
to just get into
businesses to get into people's hearts
and
minds and
thoughts and start to transform your
life it's so counterculture to our
culture today and yet I know that this
is a message for the ages that will
change people's
lives share it with somebody grow your
life everybody and we'll talk soon and
have a good
[Music]
[Applause]
one